<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-22T11:01:48+00:00</updated><id>mike-ivs.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A little blog anbout travel and techy stuff. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tasmania Part 2</title><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/tasmania2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tasmania Part 2"/><published>2025-02-15T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-15T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/tasmania2</id><content type="html" xml:base="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/tasmania2/"><![CDATA[<p>At last we found the secret to writing the blog posts: have the passenger write them up on a phone during the few hours each day of roadtripping (as long as there aren’t too many corners!).</p> <h2 id="day-6-port-arthur-to-hobart">Day 6: Port Arthur to Hobart</h2> <p>Today felt like we were back in humanity so what’s better than a quaint coffee shop and cake for morning tea. Thanks to Chloe’s dad we went to Picker pantry and had one of the best chocolate-raspberry cakes we had ever tried!</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/1.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/1.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>Our next stop was the Port Arthur Historic Site: an old mill turned into a prison. The place was huge with walks, buildings, and even a ferry ride to enjoy. We started with the boat trip which took us around the harbour and showed us the area where the young convicts, some as young as 9, were sent. We then explored the main buildings - 5 storeys of cells, churches, and officers’ houses. We could probably have spent the whole day exploring if we had had more time.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/2.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/2.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/3.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/3.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/4.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/4.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/5.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/5.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/6.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/6.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/7.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/7.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/8.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/8.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/9.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/9.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/10.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/10.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/11.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/11.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>After walking around for a good 3 hours we had worked up an appetite, so our next stops were foodie heaven! The Tasman Chocolate factory for some Belgian style delights and a rocky road Before the main lunch break at the Blue Seal pub for the local delicacy of curried scallop pies. Aussies might not have done the pastry as well as NZ but the filling was delicious.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/12.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/12.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/13.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/13.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/14.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/14.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/15.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/15.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>The final stop of the day was to see the Tasman Arch and Devils kitchen, an impressive work of nature due to the sea and soft rocks. Hopefully we can come back again in a few years to see the new cave which is forming too. We were then on our way to the capital of Tasmania Hobart for the weekend.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/16.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/16.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/17.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/17.jpg"/> </a> </div> <h2 id="day-7-hobart">Day 7: Hobart</h2> <p>No trip to Hobart is complete without a trip to MONA. A quirky art museum with weird and wonderful pieces of art. It recognises the pretentiousness of some museums and pokes fun at both the art and itself. We embraced our inner children by playing in the park before opening time. Watch the video below to make yourself laugh!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/18.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/18.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/19.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/19.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/20.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/20.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <video src="/assets/video/mona-slide.mp4" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <p>The most unique piece we found was ‘The Confession Chamber’. You walked into a spiralling corridor of noise insulation until you reached the centre, where you then spoke to people 3 storeys up outside the MONA. Anonymous confessions for some, a loving serenade for us instead!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/21.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/21.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/23.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/23.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/24.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/24.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/22.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/22.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/25.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/25.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/29.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/29.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/26.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/26.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/27.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/27.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/28.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/28.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/30.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/30.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>For lunch we went to Frogmore Creek which was a beautiful little vineyard near the Coal River recommended by one of mum’s friends. The food and wine were both phenomenal and we were very grateful to Dad for being the designated driver of big Bertha. Being guests in the back was very relaxing. Fortunately we bought a bottle of dessert wine to enjoy that evening with him.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/31.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/31.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/32.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/32.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/33.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/33.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/34.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/34.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/35.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/35.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>Post- a 3 course feast we popped across the road to Coal River Farm to get some cheese for the fanciest camp dinner I think we will have in our 3 month trip. Our 3 cheeses of choice were - Double Cream Brie, Ash Rolled Curd Cheese, and a mild blue. A delicious treat and dad could finally enjoy the wine as well.</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/36.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/36.jpg"/> </a></p> <h2 id="day-8-hobart-to-lake-burbury">Day 8: Hobart to Lake Burbury</h2> <p>Another not-to-miss adventure in Hobart is Mount Wellington. We decided to get to the summit via the organ pipes track. The view from the top was incredible despite being a bit rainy and cloudy. We were glad we carried out jumpers though because it was flipping cold and windy too! After 2 delicious days of hospitality we were back to camping food so a picnic lunch at the Springs car park was in line. We did however get a delicious coffee and hot chocolate to warm us up.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/37.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/37.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/38.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/38.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/39.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/39.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>A long drive ahead of us made Lake saint Clair a beautiful pit stop for a cuppa in the van and a wee stroll to try and spot that elusive platypus once more. No success despite the logbook of sightings at the information centre… the saga continues!! On our drive to the Lake Burbury Camp ground we spotted wombats and echidnas at the side of the road, but of course pictures were nigh on impossible.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/40.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/40.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/41.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/41.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>Lake Burbury itself was beautiful and Chloe and I went for a sunset swim in the fresh water lake. Cold but so refreshing after a long day. We met some lovely couples who told us about the walks in cradle mountain and some things up in Queensland worth seeing as well. Camping people are so friendly!</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/42.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/42.jpg"/> </a></p> <h2 id="day-9-lake-burbury-to-ulverstone">Day 9: Lake Burbury to Ulverstone</h2> <p>Tuesday took us to another Tasmania National Park: Cradle Mountain. On the way to the NP we could smell a lot of smoke and after we read the news we realised there was a bush fire around Lake St Clair which had closed some of the main tracks. Crazy to think we were actually so close but didn’t see it!</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/43.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/43.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>Stroll number one at Cradle Mountain was the Enchanted walk: a riverside stroll with the ever-fleeting promise to spot a platypus. You’ve probably guessed it by now - no platypus sightings. Despite this we knew straight away why the walk was enchanted because in the first 300m we saw 2 black tiger snakes much to dad’s disgust. We were worried about what the rest of the hikes had in store but we thankfully didn’t see any more!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/43a.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/43a.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/44.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/44.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/45.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/45.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>A picnic lunch at Dove Lake followed by a couple of walks either side of the lake’s visitor centre allowed us to see the view of Cradle Mountain and the old boat sheds. Our final stop at Cradle Mountain was Ronny’s Creek, a walk recommended to us btw couple alat Lake Burbury yesterday. It definitely did not disappoint, we were told to go around 3pm to see the wombats, and that is exactly what we saw! 2 mothers and their Joey’s and a couple of other lone wombats too. They are fast becoming Chloe’s favourite animal!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/46.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/46.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/47.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/47.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/48.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/48.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/49.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/49.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/50.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/50.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/51.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/51.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <video src="/assets/video/cradle-mountain-wombat.mp4" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Next stop Ulverstone for some much needed beach R&amp;R. We arrived around 6pm and walked to the town centre for dinner at the River Arms Hotel. Blooming delicious food and the biggest serving of sticky date pudding we have ever seen! 100% would go back again! A nice 30 minute walk back let us see a bandicoot roaming on the grass berms and at the camp site we saw 2 little penguins waddling around too.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/52.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/52.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/53.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/53.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/54.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/54.jpg"/> </a> </div> <h2 id="day-10-ulverstone">Day 10: Ulverstone</h2> <p>After a long few days of driving and hiking mum and dad decided to stay and explore around Ulverstone for the day, while Chloe and I drove west for the day.</p> <p>We made our way to Table cape for a lovely coastal view and bimble to the lighthouse. The cape is famous for tulip growing, but while we didn’t see any flowers post- season we did see a few more pademelons relaxing in the shady undergrowth on the walk.</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/55.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/55.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>Our next stop of the day was the Trowutta arch. This natural archway is a 15 minute walk into a moody forest and caused by the collapsed roofs of two large sinkholes connected by a cave system. A pretty cool place, and the photos don’t convey the scale of the arch, but certainly not a place for a skinny dip.</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/56.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/56.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>With the archway off our to-do list it was time to address the real reason we drove out west: to visit the butcher shop of MasterChef Australia’s 2024 runner up. We’d been rooting for the “meat and two veg” Josh ‘Pezza’ Perry ever since he survived his first dessert pressure test, and when we found out he was a butcher on Tassie we vowed to visit! While we didn’t hatch a glimpse of Pezza we did stock up on sausages and steak for dinner, and a slab of bacon for breakfast.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/57.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/57.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/58.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/58.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/59.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/59.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>On our drive back to the campsite we decided to call into the town of Penguin. That’s right, it’s a town called Penguin. And as you’d expect they fully embraced their name with homages to penguins everywhere you looked. We even visited the Penguin Brewery and while their core range wasn’t to my hoppy tastes their raspberry sour was pretty good.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/60.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/60.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/63.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/63.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/62.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/62.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/61.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/61.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/64.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/64.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>That evening we reunited with mum and dad at the campsite and had a BBQ with the sausages and steak from the butchers which was delicious! We rounded off the evening by taking our camping chairs down to the beach, waiting for dusk, and watching half a dozen little penguins make their way back to their nests. A cracking end to the day!</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/65.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/65.jpg"/> </a></p> <video style="width:100%" src="/assets/video/phillip-penguins.mp4" controls=""></video> <h2 id="day-11-ulverstone-to-launceston">Day 11: Ulverstone to Launceston</h2> <p>Our final full day in Tasmania but we were determined to make the most of it . We left the campsite and made our way to Devonport for a bit of sightseeing. It wasn’t our cup of tea when we arrived, so we simply went for a stroll along the waterfront and carried on our journey.</p> <p>We called in at the House of Anvers chocolate place for a pitstop and a delicious dose of unhealthy goodness. The hot chocolate met my high Belgian choc standards and the cakes left us all very full!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/66.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/66.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/67.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/67.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/68.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/68.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>In need of a walk to burn off our cocoa overdose we decided to visit the Warrawee reserve for a riverside walk to an epic swing bridge. This decision had absolutely nothing to do with the fact that it was a known platypus location…</p> <p>Chances for wildlife spotting looked high when Chloe saw a Tasmanian devil run across the road on the drive in. En-route to the bridge we saw pademelons and wallabies in the bushes, and even an echidna waddling by the river side (a blurry photo is my only proof!). The swing bridge itself was an impressive beast that even dad couldn’t sway (despite his best attempts!) and from it we could see the occasional patch of bubbles reaching the river surface.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/69.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/69.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/70.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/70.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/71.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/71.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>We stayed on the bridge for around 20 minutes: long enough to still not see a platypus! After a walk back to the vans we set off on our journey and Chloe took us on a slight detour to finally see the elusive creature! This was the last main stop in our Tassie adventure but we popped off the main road to get Dad some honey we had promised him for most of the 2 weeks only to find it was a small but cute shack at someone’s house! We did however both buy some delicious raw honey.</p> <p>Once we arrived and set up for our final night in Hadson we decided to get a pizza takeaway. Turns out they were the friendliest pizza guys ever and the family pizzas were flipping delicious. They gave us some tips to spot platypus so we went to the local campground to try but once again the platypus eluded us!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/72.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/72.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/73.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/73.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/74.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/74.jpg"/> </a> </div> <h2 id="day-12-back-to-melbourne">Day 12: Back to Melbourne</h2> <p>The day had arrived for us to finish our Tasmania road trip and head back to the mainland. We packed up into our bags, swept up the van, and departed for the airport. A painless campervan dropoff and we were dropping our bags and boarding the flight to Melbourne with a background aroma of smoke from the St. Clair’s wildfires.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/75.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/75.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250215/76.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250215/s/76.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>So long Tassie it’s been a blast! Stay tuned for our next post as we say goodbye to my parents and finally hit the road in our 3-month campervan.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel"/><category term="AUS"/><category term="SixMonthTravel"/><category term="Tasmania"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Tasmania with my parents]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tasmania Part 1</title><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/tasmania1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tasmania Part 1"/><published>2025-02-14T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-14T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/tasmania1</id><content type="html" xml:base="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/tasmania1/"><![CDATA[<p>If you hadn’t guessed from the delay since the last post we’ve been pretty busy having fun! We’ll likely try to keep the posts shorter in the future as it takes oh so much time to type up and, mostly to blame, to collate and prep several sources of images.</p> <p>Without further ado, the first half of our Tasmania journey!</p> <h2 id="day-1-launceston">Day 1: Launceston</h2> <p>An early start and a cosy drive in a Kia Picanto with 4 sets of luggage, 4 passengers and 4 pieces of hand luggage we headed back to Melbourne airport for our flight to Launceston, Tasmania. We rented this interesting-looking camper from Auto rent but it was perfect in the end, and the 4WD came into good use on a 20km gravel road!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/1.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/1.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/2.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/2.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/3.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/3.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>Our first stop in Launceston was the Cateract Gorge. A “short walk” from the Big4 campsite but on a hot and sunny day the uphill walk to the gorge felt brutal! We started by taking the cable car up the mountain side, over the top of the swimming pool and lake. Some beautiful views and at the top we saw our first wallaby! Oh and some peacocks…! From there we went up to a view point over the gorge before taking the ZigZag track towards town. We saw some crazy people jumping into the gorge from about 6m up but none of us were brave enough to do it too!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/4.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/4.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/5.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/5.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/6.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/6.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>Once we made it to town, and after a stroll along the rivers edge, we made to our first (of many?) brewery stops - Du Cane Brewery. The beer was so good mum fell of her chair!! The raspberry sour would have made the beer label book if it wasn’t simply printed onto the can. We finished the day with a wander back to the campsite via the supermarket, and a dusk we were treated to a troop of Tasmanian Pademelons roaming the campsite.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/7.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/7.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/8.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/8.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/9.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/9.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/10.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/10.jpg"/> </a></p> <h2 id="day-2-launceston---bay-of-fires">Day 2: Launceston -&gt; Bay of Fires</h2> <p>We began our roadtrip in earnest by travelling from Launceston to the Bay of Fires with several stops along the way. Our first stop was at the Lilydale falls - a teaser for mum and dad of the amount of walking we would make them do! We were treated to two small waterfalls, no more than a few metres high each, and a little wallaby carving on one of the sets of stairs.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/11.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/11.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/12.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/12.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/13.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/13.JPG"/> </a> </div> <p>Our second stop of the day was at the Bridstowe lavender estate, no purple flowers in sight but an intense smell of lavender was present. The heat took over and we each had a delicious lavender-infused ice cream while walking towards the estates pond which promised possible sightings of the incredibly elusive platypus… No platypus was seen… the platypus saga begins!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/14.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/14.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/15.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/15.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>We attempted to stop at Lake Derby’s floating sauna for some R&amp;R. It turns out you really need to read up about bookings to places, so a lesson was learnt nice and early into our trip! We did find a cool suspension bridge at our lunchtime stop off though so at least it wasn’t a fully wasted drive.</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/16.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/16.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>Our final stop of the day was the Little Blue Lake - a former mining area with such a high aluminium content that the water turns vivid blue. Little, blue, and a lake, 5/5 for description! We made our way towards Cosy Corner North for an overnight stop in a picturesque free camp, and nearly led mum and dad-s poor campervan down 20km of gravel road! Thanks for the heads up Georgie! Cracking little spot to stop for the evening.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/17.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/17.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/18.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/18.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/19.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/19.JPG"/> </a> </div> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/20.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/20.jpg"/> </a></p> <h2 id="day-3-bay-of-fires---freycinet-national-park">Day 3: Bay of Fires -&gt; Freycinet National Park</h2> <p>When you wake up on the east coast there is only one thing to do - watch the sunrise. That’s exactly what Chloe did while catching up with her mum and dad on a call. Dad, also an early riser, was surprised to find a set of tracks on the beach already which led towards Chloe. While Mum and I had a ‘much needed’ lie in those two explored, and after some brekkie in the van we all went for a walk along the beach and over the incredibly orange rocks giving Bay of Fires its name.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/21.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/21.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/22.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/22.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/23.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/23.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/23a.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/23a.JPG"/> </a></p> <div class="caption"> A cool little starfish I found in a rock pool! </div> <p>Our journey along the east coast took us to the East Coast Nature World. The coastal views were quite lovely, but some plonker managed to put a grainy black and white filter on their camera at the Orange Rocks so enjoy some artsy “old fishing village” vibe photos…</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/24.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/24.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/25.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/25.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/26.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/26.JPG"/> </a> </div> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/27.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/27.JPG"/> </a></p> <div class="caption"> Camera settings finally restored to default </div> <p>The ECNW gave us the chance to see all the animals Tassie had to offer, although Dad didn’t take a shine to the Tasmanian Devils. The feisty creatures are struggling though with a type of cancer which has destroyed 70% of the population on Tasmania so there is a lot of research into how to mitigate the transmissible facial tumours. While at the park we also got to feed Forrester Kangaroos and Albino Wallabies - definitely a highlight thus far for Chloe. In typical Mikey fashion I made friends with the talking Long-billed Cockatoo in the park!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/28.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/28.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/29.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/29.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/30.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/30.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/31.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/31.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/32.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/32.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/33.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/33.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/34.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/34.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/35.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/35.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/36.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/36.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/37.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/37.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/38.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/38.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/39.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/39.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/40.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/40.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/41.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/41.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/42.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/42.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/43.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/43.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/44.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/44.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/45.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/45.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>After a busy morning, we were all ready for some lunch and the Lobster Shack in Bicheno was recommended. We had a FEAST with a lobster roll, and two fisherman’s platters to share, we wish we had taken a picture, but we were too hungry! To waddle off the food we went for a stroll to the Bicheno Blow holes. They may not have been as incredible as the Tongan ones we saw in December 2024 but it was still pretty cool and the walk over rocks following white painted arrows was unique too - pretty sure it wouldn’t be allowed in the UK.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/46.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/46.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/47.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/47.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/48.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/48.JPG"/> </a> </div> <p>A quick stop at the supermarket and another brewery - Bicheno Brewing, we made our way for a 2 night stop in Freycinet National Park. The campsite was as close to the beach as we could get and so we couldn’t resist a little dip before bedtime before a very short sleep….</p> <h2 id="day-4-freycinet-national-park">Day 4: Freycinet National Park</h2> <p>To quote my wonderful wife: “BEST HIKE EVERRRRRR”. To quote myself and my dad: “we’ll forgive you by lunchtime”.</p> <p>Chloe had been watching Instagram posts of Australia-travellers for many months before our trip, and high up on her list of must-dos was a sunrise hike to the top of Mt Amos. This meant a 3:30am start for Chloe, dad, and I with sunrise around 6:28. (mum smartly decided she’d stay and prepare breakfast for 8.30 am). The mountain range in Freycinet park is known as The Hazards. They are said to be named after a local whaler called Richard Hazard, but my alternative theory is that they are named after the pitch-black rockface scramble we undertook!</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/49a.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/49a.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>We had a refreshing 50 minute walk along the road from our campsite to the base of Mt. Amos, with the only other awake creatures being several chunky possums and a single pickup truck that passed us on the road towards the base (we weren’t the only fools to attempt the walk at this time!). We needed our torches and would do until we reached the top just in time for sunrise.</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/49.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/49.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>The return loop to the top was only 5km, with an altitude difference of about 450m, but it soon became apparent that it wasn’t your run-of-the-mill hike. The track was composed of a few dusty dirt track sections, but mostly rockface scrambles and boulder hopping up the hazards themselves. If we’d seen it in the light beforehand, we might not have done it by torchlight alone! Below are some before sunrise/after sunrise photos for comparison, although locations are very approximate as there wasn’t much reference for where I took the original photos!</p> <img-comparison-slider> <figure slot="first"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/50-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/50-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/50-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/50.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <figure slot="second"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/50a-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/50a-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/50a-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/50a.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </img-comparison-slider> <img-comparison-slider> <figure slot="first"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/52-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/52-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/52-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/52.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <figure slot="second"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/52a-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/52a-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/52a-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/52a.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </img-comparison-slider> <img-comparison-slider> <figure slot="first"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/53-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/53-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/53-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/53.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <figure slot="second"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/53a-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/53a-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/53a-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/53a.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </img-comparison-slider> <img-comparison-slider> <figure slot="first"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/54-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/54-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/54-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/54.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <figure slot="second"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/54a-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/54a-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/54a-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/54a.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </img-comparison-slider> <img-comparison-slider> <figure slot="first"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/55-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/55-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/55-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/55.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <figure slot="second"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250214/55a-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/55a-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250214/55a-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/55a.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </img-comparison-slider> <p>Eventually we reached the top of Mt. Amos in time for sunrise and tucked into a few celebratory bickies. It turns out that the pickup that passed us earlier in the morning was a father-son duo, one of which was a professional photographer trying to capture the sunrise too. The views from the top were stunning. Despite actual sunrise being scuppered by clouds on the horizon the sun did peak through 10 minutes later leading to some cracking shots and selfies. We just about forgave Chloe for the crazy scramble too! We made our way back down the mountain in daylight, and we cadged a lift of the pickup truck back to the campsite in time for breakfast.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/56.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/56.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/57.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/57.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/58.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/58.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/59.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/59.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/60.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/60.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/61.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/61.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/62.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/62.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/63.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/63.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/64.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/64.JPG"/> </a> </div> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/65.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/65.jpg"/> </a></p> <div class="caption"> The Hazards as seen in the daylight </div> <p>We had a fairly easy rest of the day: we walked over to the nearby Coles Bay for an afternoon ice cream and a bit of shopping, a bit of swimming and snorkelling on the beach (not much to see except two small stingrays), and we had pasta for dinner with salmon done on the campsite BBQ hotplates. An early night for us all. The hike was worth it.</p> <h2 id="day-5--freycinet-national-park---port-arthur">Day 5: : Freycinet National park -&gt; Port Arthur</h2> <p>We packed up our camper vans and continued our journey down the east coast from Freycinet to Port Arthur. We stopped off en-route at Triabunna to catch a ferry and spend the day on Maria Island – strongly recommended by several friends!</p> <p>We’d been promised that you were pretty much guaranteed to see a wombat on Maria Island, and even on a very warm summers day, which wombats detest, we were not disappointed! Within the first 5 minutes we’d seen a snoozing wombat, a grazing wombat, and even a little bandicoot. A little bit later we even saw a wombat scratching itself against the base of the old historical buildings on the island!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/66.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/66.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/67.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/67.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/68.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/68.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/69.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/69.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/70.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/70.JPG"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/71.JPG"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/71.JPG"/> </a> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <video src="/assets/video/maria-island-wombat.mp4" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A wiggly wombat! </div> <p>The easiest way to get around the island quickly is on bikes and so we rented some. Quite a few of you will know that bikes are not, ehem, my forte, but I persevered despite the hills, gravel and walkers. We visited the fossil cliffs, had a quick picnic lunch, went to the painted cliffs, and had one final explore of the historical buildings before we departed back for Triabunna.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/72.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/72.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/73.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/73.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/74.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/74.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/75.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/75.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250214/76.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250214/s/76.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>Once back on the main island we continued driving down to Port Arthur, successfully leading our parents van (dubbed Big Bertha) down a stretch of unsealed road. By the time we reached the “4x4 recommended” sign we had lost all phone signal to warn them…oops! All went well though and we even spotted a snuffling echidna by the side of the road before finally reaching the Port Arthur campsite.</p> <p>Part 2 of our Tasmania trip to follow soon!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel"/><category term="AUS"/><category term="SixMonthTravel"/><category term="Tasmania"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Tasmania with my parents]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring Melbourne</title><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/melbourne/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Melbourne"/><published>2025-02-03T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-03T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/melbourne</id><content type="html" xml:base="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/melbourne/"><![CDATA[<p>Our first few days in Australia were spent exploring Melbourne and the Yarra Valley with our family and friends. Great fun, but it turns out that consolidating media for the blog is far more faffy than it ought to be! Anyway:</p> <h2 id="day-1-the-yarra-valley">Day 1: The Yarra Valley</h2> <p>Our first full day of adventures took us outside of the city – Stop 1 was Olinda for coffee and scones, not particularly Australian but delicious all the same. We were celebrating Dad’s birthday, so the next stop was Many Hands winery for a tasting and lunch. What a feast! After tasting 4 different wines, the owner said for $55 we do an all you can eat style menu – Pizza, Pasta, Antipasti platter and dessert. Safe to say it really was all you can eat: 2 full pizzas, a huge antipasto, 2 sharing plates of pasta, and desserts that we had to take home!</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/1.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/1.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>Feeling like rolling we went for a beautiful walk through the Alowyn Gardens and maze where we saw the ‘lesser spotted V-flicker’ as named by Uncle Dave!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/2.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/2.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/3.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/3.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>No trip to the Yarra Valley is complete without a visit to the Yarra Valley Chocolateries so we had to give their chocolate a tasting just in case as well.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/4.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/4.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/5.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/5.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>Finishing off the day with some real wildlife spotting and a Cockatoo eating a banana on someone’s balcony. Safe to say we won’t be able to buy a house in Melbourne anytime soon!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/6a.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/6a.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/6.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/6.jpg"/> </a> </div> <h2 id="day-2-melbourne-central-extravaganza">Day 2: Melbourne Central extravaganza</h2> <p>Today we spent the day exploring with some special friends Georgina and Greg in Melbourne – our local tour guides! We started with a stroll through the botanical gardens, they really are beautiful but at 33C by 10am it was a sweaty stroll!! Melbourne is a foodie heaven we spent the day eating, drinking and exploring…again. Started at the Queen Victoria Markets trying freshly cooked jam donuts followed by a visit to the Cheese Train. A unique experience and who new coffee pairs so well with cheese. A little slice of luxury before our 3 months of beans on toast!</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/7.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/7.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/8.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/8.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/9.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/9.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>After all the eating we decide to go for a stroll around the city - the Dr Seuss gallery, Gog and Magog (very random!), Fortress Melbourne, the Yarra river, Opera in Federal square and toured the incredible street art on the laneways.</p> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/10.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/10.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/11.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/11.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/12.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/12.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/13.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/13.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/14.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/14.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/15.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/15.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/16.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/16.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/17.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/17.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/18.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/18.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/19.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/19.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/20.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/20.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/21.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/21.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/22.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/22.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/23.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/23.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/24.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/24.jpg"/> </a> </div> <p>22000 steps later we were ready for the sofa!</p> <h2 id="day-3-south-yarra-suburbs">Day 3: South Yarra Suburbs</h2> <p>Kiwi friends round 2!! We met Lucy and Alex some friends from NZ at the Prahran Markets for pastries and a catch up. These pastries challenge even the likes of Lune – look how cute the coffee croissant is. Thanks for treating us Lucy and Alex!</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/25.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/25.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>We though 33C was crazy hot on Saturday but little did we know it would hit 37C on Sunday. We went for a walk round Fawkner park at about 3pm only to have to stop for an emergency ice cream – what ‘Golden Gaytime’ it was! Blooming delicious, wish we got 2.</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/26.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/26.jpg"/> </a></p> <p>A hot day is never complete without a trip to the beach and Brighton’s Bathing boxes were on the cards for an evening stroll/swim with mum and dad. An Unexpected incoming storm quickly lit up the skies with bolts of lightning, but we didn’t let that stop us from a quick dip – The first of many Aussies swims to come. Although as Chloe’s sister pointed out we may as well have just been in the UK!</p> <p><a class="spotlight" href="/assets/img/blog/20250203/27.jpg"> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250203/s/27.jpg"/> </a></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <video src="/assets/video/melbourne-storm.mp4" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" controls=""/> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Some pretty crazy lightning off the coast! </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel"/><category term="AUS"/><category term="SixMonthTravel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first leg of our six months travel]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mā te wā, see you soon Aotearoa</title><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/matewa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mā te wā, see you soon Aotearoa"/><published>2025-01-30T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/matewa</id><content type="html" xml:base="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/matewa/"><![CDATA[<p>Our first travel blog post! Today was the day we said mā te wā/see you soon to our friends in Aotearoa and begin our travels for 2025.</p> <p>We got off to a somewhat bumpy start: while we tidied the house for the final time we found out that our 2 week campervan hire for Tasmania was “cancelled due to unforeseen repairs”… yikes! Fortunately, after a few hours and chunk of stress we managed to find a replacement and then finished the house cleaning.</p> <p>There was a silver lining when we got to the airport this afternoon - it turns out Chloë had booked our Australia flights while still an Emirates gold member meaning we got business lounge access one last time.</p> <p>We’re now in Melbourne for our first leg of our Australia travels so make sure to check in every now and then to see what we’ve been up to. Ka kite New Zealand, it’s been a blast!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250130/1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250130/2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> All packed up and ready to travel. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel"/><category term="NZ"/><category term="AUS"/><category term="SixMonthTravel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our first blog post about our travels!]]></summary></entry></feed>