<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-06T03:35:13+00:00</updated><id>mike-ivs.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A little blog anbout travel and techy stuff. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Exploring Melbourne</title><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/melbourne/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Melbourne"/><published>2025-02-03T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-03T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/melbourne</id><content type="html" xml:base="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/melbourne/"><![CDATA[<p>Our first few days in Australia were spent exploring Melbourne and the Yarra Valley with our family and friends.</p> <ul id="melbourne-days" class="tab" data-tab="e2b9d581-0339-403a-a033-8d325cf35d2e" data-name="melbourne-days"> <li class="active" id="melbourne-days-day-1"> <a href="#">Day 1 </a> </li> <li id="melbourne-days-day-2"> <a href="#">Day 2 </a> </li> <li id="melbourne-days-day-3"> <a href="#">Day 3 </a> </li> </ul> <ul class="tab-content" id="e2b9d581-0339-403a-a033-8d325cf35d2e" data-name="melbourne-days"> <li class="active"> <h2 id="the-yarra-valley">The Yarra Valley</h2> <p>Our first full day of adventures took us outside of the city – Stop 1 was Olinda for coffee and scones, not particularly Australian but delicious all the same. We were celebrating Dad’s birthday, so the next stop was Many Hands winery for a tasting and lunch. What a feast! After tasting 4 different wines, the owner said for $55 we do an all you can eat style menu – Pizza, Pasta, Antipasti platter and dessert. Safe to say it really was all you can eat: 2 full pizzas, a huge antipasto, 2 sharing plates of pasta, and desserts that we had to take home!</p> <ul> <li>Insert Many hands picture, Mike and Dad</li> </ul> <p>Feeling like rolling we went for a beautiful walk through the Alowyn Gardens and maze where we saw the ‘lesser spotted V-flicker’ as named by Uncle Dave!</p> <ul> <li>Insert Lesser spotted V pic, tiny fountain</li> </ul> <p>No trip to the Yarra Valley is complete without a visit to the Yarra Valley Chocolateries so we had to give their chocolate a tasting just in case as well.</p> <ul> <li>insert Mikey eating chocolate bar, koala and kanga chocolate</li> </ul> <p>Finishing off the day with some real wildlife spotting and a Cockatoo eating a banana on someone’s balcony. Safe to say we won’t be able to buy a house in Melbourne anytime soon!</p> <ul> <li>Insert Cockatoo pic, cost pic</li> </ul> </li> <li> <h2 id="melbourne-central-extravaganza">Melbourne Central extravaganza</h2> <p>Today we spent the day exploring with some special friends Georgina and Greg in Melbourne – our local tour guides! We started with a stroll through the botanical gardens, they really are beautiful but at 33C by 10am it was a sweaty stroll!! Melbourne is a foodie heaven we spent the day eating, drinking and exploring…again. Started at the Queen Victoria Markets trying freshly cooked jam donuts followed by a visit to the Cheese Train. A unique experience and who new coffee pairs so well with cheese. A little slice of luxury before our 3 months of beans on toast!</p> <ul> <li>Insert Jam donut photo, cheese train video, botanical gardens gate photo</li> </ul> <p>After all the eating we decide to go for a stroll around the city - the Dr Seuss gallery, Gog and Magog (very random!), Fortress Melbourne the Yarra river, Opera in Federal square and toured the incredible street art on the laneways.</p> <ul> <li>Insert River, Gog/Magog, fortress, street art, Dr Seuss</li> </ul> <p>22000 steps later we were ready for the sofa!</p> </li> <li> <h2 id="south-yarra-suburbs">South Yarra Suburbs</h2> <p>Kiwi friends round 2!! We met Lucy and Alex some friends from NZ at the Prahran Markets for pastries and a catch up. These pastries challenge even the likes of Lune – look how cute the coffee croissant is. Thanks for treating us Lucy and Alex!</p> <p>-Insert Coffee croissant</p> <p>We though 33C was crazy hot on Saturday but little did we know it would hit 37C on Sunday <em>hot emoji</em> We went for a walk round Fawkner park at about 3pm only to have to stop for an emergency ice cream – what ‘Golden Gaytime’ it was! Blooming delicious, wish we got 2.</p> <ul> <li>Insert 37C picture, golden gaytime pic</li> </ul> <p>A hot day is never complete without a trip to the beach and Brighton’s Bathing boxes were on the cards for an evening stroll/swim with mum and dad. An Unexpected incoming storm quickly lit up the skies with bolts of lightning, but we didn’t let that stop us from a quick dip – The first of many Aussies swims to come. Although as Chloe’s sister pointed out we may as well have just been in the UK!</p> <p>Insert - Video of storm, beach boxes</p> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250130/1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250130/2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> All packed up and ready to travel. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel"/><category term="AUS"/><category term="SixMonthTravel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first leg of our six months travel]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mā te wā, see you soon Aotearoa</title><link href="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/matewa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mā te wā, see you soon Aotearoa"/><published>2025-01-30T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/matewa</id><content type="html" xml:base="mike-ivs.github.io/blog/2025/matewa/"><![CDATA[<p>Our first travel blog post! Today was the day we said mā te wā/see you soon to our friends in Aotearoa and begin our travels for 2025.</p> <p>We got off to a somewhat bumpy start: while we tidied the house for the final time we found out that our 2 week campervan hire for Tasmania was “cancelled due to unforeseen repairs”… yikes! Fortunately, after a few hours and chunk of stress we managed to find a replacement and then finished the house cleaning.</p> <p>There was a silver lining when we got to the airport this afternoon - it turns out Chloë had booked our Australia flights while still an Emirates gold member meaning we got business lounge access one last time.</p> <p>We’re now in Melbourne for our first leg of our Australia travels so make sure to check in every now and then to see what we’ve been up to. Ka kite New Zealand, it’s been a blast!</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/1-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250130/1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/20250130/2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/20250130/2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> All packed up and ready to travel. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel"/><category term="NZ"/><category term="AUS"/><category term="SixMonthTravel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our first blog post about our travels!]]></summary></entry></feed>